CONTACT

jasoncooper@outlook.com (202) 491-5904 13439 Riverside Drive, Apt B Sherman Oaks, CA 91423 linkedin.com/in/jasonrcooper/

SUMMARY

Technical professional with significant expertise shipping digital products and campaigns on a mission-orientated, non-profit budget. Strong social intelligence, empathy, good-humor, and conflict-resolution skills that help turn colleagues into families. Adept translator of technology details into plain-speak, user stories into business requirements, and customer desires into wireframes and product features.

EDUCATION

B.A. in Political Science from Oakland University, Rochester, MI Internship at the Office of U.S. Senator Carl Levin, Warren, MI

TECHNICAL

Agile and Scrum practices HTML/CSS/JavaScript MySQL Git Trello Google Ads Google Analytics Google Search Console Google Suite Salesforce Salesforce Marketing Cloud MailChimp Microsoft Office 365 Microsoft Teams Slack Adobe Dreamweaver Adobe InDesign Adobe Photoshop Adobe XD

Jason Cooper

Product management, digital marketing, leadership & mentorship.

Career Experience

KABOOM! is an innovative, entrepreneurial non-profit dedicated to ending playspace inequity.

I've led, managed, or informed every aspect of our digital footprint for the past 13 years, including our web apps, kaboom.org, social media presences, email marketing, measurement, and analysis.

Director, Digital & Creative Services | Los Angeles, CA 2017-Current

- Led the digital rebranding of KABOOM! to express and promote an organization-wide brand evolution.
- Combined the digital and creative teams into a singular, cooperative unit unifying KABOOM! print and digital brand expression.
- Managed and mentored successful digital and creative teams.
- Analyzed website analytics, social media performance, and email marketing campaigns to engage user communities and improve conversion rates.
- Served on organization's leadership team, informing organization's strategy, mentoring staff, and fostering an inclusive and equitable environment.
- Managed day-to-day collateral and video production.
- Product managed and shipped bi-weekly iterations of web properties.

Associate Director, Digital Engagement | Los Angeles, CA 2015-2017

- Revamped kaboom.org improving average time spent on website by 50%, number of visits by 18%, decreased bounce rate by 4%.
- Led digital production of organization-wide publications such as: Annual Reports (2014-2018) and KABOOM! Play Everywhere Playbook (kaboom.org/playbook).
- Provided leadership and conception to the national Play Everywhere Challenge, a playspace design program to transform everyday spaces into places for kids to play.
- Led the creation of tools to manage the America's Most Playful Family Contest, a national search to discover playful families and award them a Disney Parks vacation.
- Led programming for staff retreats, including planning, event design, video production, program development, A/V production and master of ceremonies.

↓ Continued

JASON COOPER

jasoncooper@outlook.com (202) 491-5904 13439 Riverside Drive, Apt B Sherman Oaks, CA 91423 linkedin.com/in/jasonrcooper/

PUBLIC SPEAKING

Geek and Sundry International Tabletop Day live stream, Apr 2016 Esteemed, on-air guest during "International TableTop Day" programming; online event raised nearly \$30,000 within 24 hours.

Points of Light Conference on Volunteering & Service, June 2012 Speaker: "Tips & Tools for Building Engaged Online Communities"

Nonprofit Technology Network (NTEN) Annual Conference, Apr 2012

Speaker: "Online Tools to Transform Communities"

D.C. Social Media Summit, Center for Non-Profit Success, May 2011 Panelist: "Facebook 201"

Life after AmeriCorps Conference, Serve D.C., Feb 2011 Speaker: "Navigating Social Media"

Career Experience, cont.

Senior Manager, Content & Product | Washington D.C. 2012-2015

- Reorganized external digital team into an in-house Software Engineering Unit significantly cutting costs and improving outcomes of digital campaigns and product upgrades.
- Managed technical and business requirements to translate them into defined user stories for developers.
- Launched new Kontent Management System (KMS), a Ruby on Rails content management system, to power KABOOM! website (kaboom. org).
- Launched Our Dream Playground, a DIY playground project management and fundraising tool for users to develop playground projects (ourdreamplayground.kaboom.org).
- Launched national Map of Play directory of playgrounds, with over 100,000 mapped playspaces and tens of thousands of user (mapofplay.kaboom.org).
- Initiated and established Agile product development methods resulting in improved applications' security and overall functionality enhancement.

Coordinator, Quality Assurance | Washington D.C. 2011-2012

- Pivoted digital products towards user-centric designs and data-driven decision making.
- Ensured every release was bug-free, developed documentation for products and introduced Agile practices to product development.

Coordinator, Online Community | Washington D.C.

 Built and maintained organization's presence and positive reputation across social media channels. Developed follower base from zero into thousands.

Professional Development

- Phase One Equity Training Racial Equity Institute, Dec 2018
- UX Design Edge Training Everett McKay, Nov 2011
- Google Seminars for Success Alex Broussard, EpikOne, Jun 2009